<xml>
	<recipe name="Bavarian Mints">
		<ingredient_list>
			<ingredient> 1 1/2 pounds chocolate</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 cup heavy cream</ingredient>
			
		</ingredient_list>
		<directions>
 Heat oven to lowest temperature (110) then turn off.  Put chocolate in small mixing bowl, then place in oven until melted.  Heat cream to lukewarm.  Add cream to chocolate all at once.  Beat with mixer, slowly at first to prevent splattering, until well mixed (1/2 to 1 minute).  Add either 1/2 teaspoon vanilla or 3 to 5 drops oil of peppermint (not spearmint!).  Pour into buttered 9" pan.  Chill 2-3 days (at least 12 hours). 
		</directions>
	</recipe>
	<recipe name="Caramel">
		<ingredient_list>
			<ingredient> 2 cups sugar</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 cup dark Karo corn syrup</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 cube (1/2 cup) butter</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1/2 pint cream</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1/2 pint cream</ingredient>
			
		</ingredient_list>
		<directions>
 Rub pan and wood spoon with Nucoa margarine.  Cook sugar, corn syrup, butter, and half the cream at medium high heat to 224 (pecan roll) or 226 (caramel).  Add the other half of the cream and cook to 228 (pecan roll) or 230 (caramel).  Pour into buttered 9x13 pandont scrape the pan!  (Temperatures adjusted for 4000 feet altitude). 
		</directions>
	</recipe>
	<recipe name="Cashew Brittle (newspaper)">
		<ingredient_list>
			<ingredient> 2 cups (9.5 oz.) roasted, salted cashew halves</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 cup sugar</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1/2 cup light corn syrup</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 teaspoon butter</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 teaspoon vanilla</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 teaspoon baking soda</ingredient>
			
		</ingredient_list>
		<directions>
 In a 2-quart microwave-save bowl, stir together nuts, sugar, and corn syrup.  Microwave on high, uncovered until the mixture is light brown (about 6-8 minutes), stirring well halfway through.  While microwaving, grease cookie sheet.  Remove nut mixture from oven (warning: it will be very hot!).  Stir in butter and vanilla.  Microwave on high 1 1/2 to 2 more minutes until the mixture is caramel colored.  Remove from microwave.  Add baking soda and stir quickly until light and foamy and the soda is thoroughly mixed in.  Pour onto cookie sheet using the back of a spoon to spread out as quickly as possible (brittle will be fairly thick).  Let stand until completely cool (about 30 minutes) and break into pieces.  Store in airtight container. 
		</directions>
	</recipe>
	<recipe name="Fondant: Melted Cordial">
		<ingredient_list>
			<ingredient> 1 1/2 cups water</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1/3 cup light corn syrup</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 4 cups sugar</ingredient>
			<ingredient> pinch of salt</ingredient>
			
		</ingredient_list>
		<directions>
 Set aside a 9"x13" ungreased baking pan.  Combine ingredients in a 4-quart saucepan.  Place over high heat and stir with a wooden spoon until mixture comes to a boil.  Wash down sides of pan with a wet pastry brush (note: crystals will form really easily in this recipe if the sugar is not completely dissolved).  Cook without stirring to 240 (soft-ball stage).  Remove from heat, pour into baking pan without stirring or scraping.  Without excess movement, place in cool area.  When no longer warm, stir with wooden spoon until changes (note: this is really stiff and we use our heavy-duty mixer; alternatively wrap it in plastic wrap or cover with a damp towel and let rest 15-45 minutes).  Use immediately, or wrap in plastic and store in cool place for up to several weeks. To make cordials, dry about 125 maraschino cherries fairly thoroughly.  Melt fondant with tablespoon of maraschino cherry juice (150).  Can also add almond extract.  Dip cherries in fondant, put on wax paper.  Dip in chocolate immediately.  Centers will turn to liquid in minutes to weeks depending on how juicy the cherries were. 
		</directions>
	</recipe>
	<recipe name="Fondant: Pecan Roll Centers">
		<ingredient_list>
			<ingredient> 3 cups sugar</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 1/2 cups cream</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 3 tablespoons light Karo corn syrup</ingredient>
			<ingredient> dash salt</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 3 tablespoons butter</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 1/2 teaspoon vanilla</ingredient>
			
		</ingredient_list>
		<directions>
 Cook to 230 (already adjusted for altitude?).  Pour on marble slab (or into a pan) to cool.  Do not scrape pan (at least, do it onto something else).  Dot with butter.  Work with spoon or hands until changes consistency (note: candy will heat up and become sticky, then it will turn white instead of clear, and lose its stickiness becoming sort of the consistency of frosting).  Work in vanilla.  Roll into logs and wrap in wax paper. 
		</directions>
	</recipe>
	<recipe name="Fudge (Grandpa Armstrong)">
		<ingredient_list>
			<ingredient> 5 cups sugar</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 1/4 cup evaporated milk</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 1/4 cup water</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 3 bars Hershey's baking chocolate</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 2 1/2 teaspoons vanilla</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 2 (?) tablespoons butter</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 cup nuts (or as many as you like)</ingredient>
			
		</ingredient_list>
		<directions>
 Put sugar, milk, and water into large pan (it bubbles up).  Grate (finely chop) chocolate into pan and stir before heating.  Cover pan with lid and heat at medium high.  Do not stir until boiling, then stir occasionally; also wash down sides with water.  Cook to 220-222 (medium soft ball).  Cool quickly in metal pan or on marble slab.  When barely warm, beat with wooden spoon until set up.  Mix in 2 1/2 teaspoons vanilla.  With buttered hands, mix in nuts and mold into 5 or 6 logs. 
		</directions>
	</recipe>
	<recipe name="Rocky Road">
		<ingredient_list>
			<ingredient> 1 1/2 pounds milk chocolate</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 2-3 cups pecans</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 2-3 cups miniature marshmallows</ingredient>
			
		</ingredient_list>
		<directions>
 Turn on oven to lowest setting (110).  Break chocolate into pieces.  When oven reaches temperature, turn it off.  Put chocolate in oven until melted (20 minutes).  Stir in nuts and marshmallows.  Spread on waxed paper covered cookie sheet.  Freeze until firm.  Keep frozen until ready to serve.  Break into bite size pieces. 
		</directions>
	</recipe>
	<recipe name="Toffee (Delbert's Butter Toffee)">
		<ingredient_list>
			<ingredient> 1 pound sweet cream butter</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 2/3 cup water</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 2 cups sugar</ingredient>
			<ingredient> 1 cup chopped almonds</ingredient>
			
		</ingredient_list>
		<directions>
 Butter 12"x18" baking sheet.  In electric frying pan, combine butter and water.  Set temperature on highest setting.  Add sugar and stir constantly with a wooden spoon until mixture comes to a boil.  Wash down sides of pan wit a wet pastry brush.  Add almonds and stir until they turn golden brownabout 290 on candy thermometer.  Pour into prepared pan and let stand at room temperature to cool completely.  Optionally spread top of candy with melted chocolate and finely chopped nuts; turn over and repeat. Note about the temperature.  Because it is so shallow, it is really hard to read the temperature on the electric fry pan with a candy thermometer.  Most have an automatic temperature control which can be used as a general guide.  The best guide is really the color.  The candy starts to turn light brown, but if poured out at this stage it isn't quite done.  If you wait until it is definitely brown, it is too late and the candy will taste burnt and be too hard.  We do it by compromise.  Dad wants to dump it too early, but Mom wants to wait.  So, we wait until Dad can't stand it anymore and finally convinces Mom that it needs to be dumped.  I dont know if well ever be able to make this right without both of us.

		</directions>
		<directions>

		</directions>
	</recipe>
</xml>
